<topics>

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-new-york-city-skyscrapers</id>
    <results>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94052989/1892-06-13/ed-1/?sp=2</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        A NARROW SKY-SCRAPER.
        The Keimirk .hi- 'iSiiilttltir; to lie Erected
        In Sew York City.
        Perhaps the greatest curiosity in the
        building line ever designed to be erected in
        this city Is the new building of the Home
        Life Insurance Company,
        which will soon be under
        way on Broadway, near
        the corner of Slurry street.
        The plans wero drawn by
        Napoleon le Brun Sons,
        architect., selected in a
        competition between nine
        famous architects.
        The elevation, with a
        width of only 30 feet G
        inches on Broadway,
        shows a building of 12
        stories surmounted with
        a high gable roof, the ter
        minating finial of wliich
        will bo about is? feet
        above tlio sidewalk. The
        cornices of the building
        will be IC7 feet 3 inches In
        height from the street,
        and will not be quite as
        ____, although the roof
        will rise above the walls
        of the new Postal Tele
        graph Company's build
        ing alongside.
        The first story of the
        new 'tin- will have a
        celling height of 18 feet 6
        inches and will be ar
        ranged fur counting-room
        or banking purposes. The
        second story, to be used
        as the offices of the com
        pany, will be 23 feet 3
        inches in height on the
        Broad-fa* tront, and will
        have main and mezzanine
        floors in the rear. The
        depth of the building will
        bo 107 feet 6 inches, ami
        It will abut against the L
        of the Postal Telegraph
        Company's building.
        ln stylo the building
        will be of the severest
        kind of early Italian re
        naissance, and will be ab
        solutely fireproof. It will
        be thoroughly equipped
        with all the molern appli
        ances. The material for
        the front will probably be some shade of
        light brick. With the exception of the
        Tower Building, on lower Broadway, this
        is the narrowest high building in America.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062245/1902-07-20/ed-1/?sp=29</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        on a day like this If you dont like the
        Flatlron well hae it pulled down
        They might at least have left a little
        park there One of those Isles nf sar nr
        at a busy corner only more beautiful
        lou mean a sort of nenlnsuls nf
        safety with arm chairs for nervous
        ladles to drop right into after rmb
        the acnue and dodging the traffic Yes
        ana they could hae park attendants on
        hand with municipal smelling salts
        I dont care There should be a little
        park there with some fine monument or
        statue Then it would be almost as
        beautiful as our own Copley Square at
        home only different
        There I knew joud rine in Cnnlev
        Square before jou got through Eery
        bodjH know youre from Boston now
        Then they crossed Twent -third Strorr
        and went down Fifth Avenue she lin
        gering at the hook store and nlrtnrp
        store windows and he looking for a
        restaurant
        Did ou hear them chewing the rag
        about that building asked the big
        as being In some way a part of Great
        Britain and Americans had to pass as
        Englishmen because the brown men
        could not identify them in any other
        way
        THE TLUES WASHINGTON SUNDAY JULY 20 1902
        it used to be I wish the architects of
        that Flatlron had Inj Job for about half
        a day to answer questions about it
        Then the rush across the aenue got
        to the proper authorities without com
        ment probably thinking that qverjbody
        knew the consul as well as he dots
        But matters were confused and the
        committee reported that the King of
        Slam was to pay us a visit- and asked
        for an appropriation to entertain him
        thestnrv and began all over again finally
        getting the right answer twenty stories
        and an attic and adding There might
        be a cellar
        Now what do you think of that
        asked the cop when he cot a breathlne
        spell Some folks are actually timid
        about that building and aro afraid it
        will fall down or blow oicr Wouldnt
        take an office In It rent free
        Wc had a small hurricane hern Mow
        ing around this corner the other day
        and one man who came along wouldnt
        go by He said that building wasnt
        V 5S3H
        Yes you think that Just because a
        building is high its all right The Par
        thenon
        Now hold on No Parthenon In mine
        A View From an Upper Stoty
        a little more lively than usual and the
        policeman had to stop talking for pub
        lication and attend strictly to business
        waving back carriages horse and horse
        less starting them ahead holding up
        trolley cars pulling and pushing shop
        pers and waging his tongue as fast as
        his arms were going as follows
        Hurry madam Hold that horse
        back Its twenty stories high Yes
        yes its the Tlatlron Go ahead with
        that auto Now ladi rows oiir
        chance Twenti stories Dont knn
        what It cost Stop that car Three hun
        dred feet high Wait a minute Now
        quick madam Longer on Broadway
        than Fifth Avenue side Yes regular
        triangle Who said cuneiform Hold
        those horses or Ill run jou In Flat
        iron
        Youd thought that that skyscraper
        had been put up on purpose to fall
        down on that fellows head and that
        there was a man on tho Broadway side
        waiting to push it over That fellow
        was kind of a fool I guess Some say
        they wouldnt have an office In there
        rent free but hes the only one Ive
        struck who was afraid to go by
        Some think the flatlron Is the most
        wonderful thing in the way of engin
        eering and architecture they ever saw
        They all think something Why they
        talk about that flatiron more than they
        do about the King of Enirlnnl tti
        sick just when they were going to crown
        The original plan to have the whole
        THE UNITED STATES TO ENTERTAIN ROYaTtTT
        J 1
        pan from whom a
        successor to the
        throne woull be chosen should the Mi
        kado dlo leaving no heir He is one of
        the greatest men in Japan a cousin of
        the emperor and was made
        of the forces of the empire
        at tho close of the Chlno Japanese war
        He vlsllcd England as a special am
        bassador rt the time of tbo Queens
        Jubilee in 1SS7
        Trlnco Chen cousin of the Emperor
        of China also an envoy to the now-deferred
        coronation will visit us on his
        way home with a suite of ten nobles
        WXri HgTMlaaH
        Iff 4 1 vHwP i -v
        PRINCESS KOMATSTJ
        half of whom were educated in the
        United States Ho
        is n rv
        i r vo
        slve man speaking English fluently He
        Is well known by reason of having been
        the envoy chosen to bear the apologies
        ot vnina to Germany for the murder of
        Baron Kettler
        Prince Boris Vladimlrovltch of Rus
        sia grandson of Alexander II and
        cousin of the Czar will snend t mu
        of July In this country arriving at San
        Francisco and crossing i i
        leisurely his tour including tho Yellow
        stone Park His visit Is wholly In
        formal so that with the execptloa of
        a call upon the President which Mr
        Itoosevclt will go to Newport to rocvlve
        there will bo no ofllcla INcognitlon of
        his presence In the country
        Prince Boris Is attended by Lieuten
        ant Frederic and Lieutenant Greaves
        Of the Bed HllSRnrw nt 1 r
        VUM imperial
        Guard Lieutenant Strandtman of tho
        bharrshooters of the imperial family
        Chevalier Schack attache and Mr Con
        stantine Greaves official secretary
        flatlron building ready for occUDanc
        In September has been modified Two
        sample floors thi twelfth and sixteenth
        will be finished by that time The other
        floors will be left unfinished so far as
        the arrangement by rooms Is concerned
        until after they are let and then com
        pleted according to the desires of the
        tenants
        One of the building foremen went up
        to the twentieth floor the other day
        when there was a gale of wind blowing
        and tested the structure bybraclng his
        back against one of the columns He
        fMRfll0a53KRI 1
        iS5mBaaaBaaaaSBtt
        I
        r j
        A Bowr on View
        reported that there was not the least
        trace of swajing only a very slight
        tremor
        This building said the foreman
        will stand any wind that ever blows
        There is special construction for Just
        that purpose and the whole building is
        wind braced with heavy elrdera from
        foundation to roof If it ever goes over
        it will go all la one piece You cant
        break or bend It
        I
        fj
        10ST UNIQUE AND HOST TALKQXF BUILDING IN THE WORLD
        I patch is worth about 2000000 Youlliccman at the crossing who saves the
        Shaped Lite an Old Time
        Flatlron and I lence Call
        ed ylh FlaHron Build
        ing is Twenlv Sto
        ries High and Located ar
        the Point -in New Yorh
        Where Aorc Persons
        Pass Than Theij Do Any
        where Else in the Ae
        tropolis Built Lihe a Bat
        tleship and Looks Lihe
        the Hull ofa Trans-Atlantic
        Steamer
        THE most remarkable building in
        tho world is a twenty story
        X skyscraper that has Just been
        erected in the heart or New
        York city The structuro is shaped
        like a long and narrow letter V It
        towers high above all the buildings in
        the neighborhood and from the north
        looks eo frail by reason of its great
        height and extreme narrowness that one
        almost fears a good puff of wind would
        blow it over
        No structure cTer put up In the me
        tropolisthe acknowledged home of
        wonderful buildings has attracted as
        much attention as has this one nnii
        knots of people staring up at it may
        be seen in the -vicinity at all hours
        More persons pass the Junction of
        Broadway Fifth Avenue and Twentj
        third Street every day than any other
        point In New York It is right here
        that this wonderful building stands
        cause of its peculiar shape it has become
        to be popularly known as the flat
        iron
        Tho structure arouses considerably
        more comment on the part of visitors to
        the metropolis than anything else in
        New York The workmen on the ground
        the crossing policemen and the shop
        keepers in the vicinity are deluged with
        one continual string of questions and
        chatter regarding the building Ever one
        has something to say about it The fol
        lowing is a fair specimen of what is con
        tinually being said of tho peculiar-looking
        structure
        There is the Flatlron Building he
        fcaid as they reached the curb on the
        north side of Twenty third Street in
        inclr stroll down Fifth Avenue
        Its a shame she said
        She is studjing architecture and chic
        improvement because she likes to and
        has lots of ideas about such thincs
        Theyd better call It the old-fashioned
        name sadiron I suppose its
        iron and Im sure its sad she went
        on
        Whj V
        Why Why should they put a great
        big wedge like that right up there where
        the two greatest streets in the world
        cross each other Couldnt tbey let a
        little triangular patch of ground like
        that go to good green grass
        Ic heard that that little triangular
        can get grass lands for about a dollar
        an acre if jou go far enough out of
        town
        I dont care If Its worth four mil
        lions she said getting Indlgmnt
        Money isnt ev erj thing
        Its a wonderful building
        It Isnt beautiful Its Just a great
        chunk Why dont they call it the pie
        building It looks like a piece
        You might at least call it chocolate
        cake Its got twenty stories I mean
        lajers
        lives of thousands of women every week
        bj piloting them from enrh tn enrh
        Well Its the 3arae war all day long
        Some folks like that building and
        some dont but most all think Ifu minor
        when the first see it It sort of hursts
        on em suddenly and theyll stop right
        ir me middle of the tracks to rubber at
        It Its made this post twice as hard as
        fiafSSalxHh 1 From the Front and a Little to One Side
        i fJmmygm
        The building faces if the point
        ivyRpoHK j of the flatlron may properly be termed
        1 Its face on Tnenty thlrd Street one of
        tSmWOtml lhe greatest thoroughfares In the city
        J The two long sides of the bitildlnir are
        en Broadvray and Tlfth Avenue the two
        greatest streets of America The- rear
        of the building is on Twentv seeond
        Street
        On the Twenty third Street side the
        structure comes to a point so sharp
        that there Is scarcely room for a win
        dow The buildlne in irwnr nnvs r
        semDles the hull of a huge
        steamer The prow alms north
        at the famous Madison Square and
        there Is a long vists up Fifth Avenue
        and up Broadway Looking In this di
        rection from one of the upper windows
        the pople walking in the stret belov
        look like tho tiniest pigmies and the
        passing cabs and electric cars like
        miniature playthings
        The sides of the flatlron cover an en
        tire block They are 200 feet lone The
        rear of the building is eighty five feet
        wide The height of the building ex
        clusive of the ornamental owers and
        turrets which will surmount It will
        be when completed more thtn 300 feet
        The exterior wall area exposed to the
        wind on the Fifth Avenue side is 51004
        square feet and on the Broadway side
        about 19000 On the Twenty second
        Street end the base of the triangle
        which is but S4 feet long the area of
        the outer wall is 23000 snuare feet
        This unique structure has been built
        on the same lines as a steel battle
        ship It has an enormous steel frame
        the heaviest and strongest ever de
        signed for ship or ballding From ita
        resemblance to a huge ship some on
        nautically inclined recently figured out
        that the flatiron has a sail area of
        60000 square feet The outside of tha
        buildins is of stone
        As everyone knows the value of land
        in the heart of New Tork can be calcu
        lated as diamonds are appraised Tho
        Tlnt nF lnml ltl 1 W 1
        stands merely the ground the building
        covers cost the builders considerably
        more man i uuuviu
        The structure will bo an office build-
        Plfh ThoM rrfll n KantAl nlan
        on some of the floors entire suites of
        rooms and on the ground floor ther
        wllPbe stores to let The building will
        h fltfT r n i ilavla fn Iia aakt
        fort of business men The elevators in
        iae liaiiron win run It is said at a
        higher speed tlan those of any other
        building in America
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085488/1903-04-04/ed-1/?sp=9</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85047084/1903-07-28/ed-1/?sp=6</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        The New York Times
        i
        fc-v W;r--;l -1 J :"-TiWwii ,Jai'-,-i -;iSss,u
        is- -U; 5 iff! 'tfCf-Y ;5fl2 iMi 1 uawgv-Wi
        tip-town from Newspaper Row. Its new home, which is being built at the junction of Broad
        4 way, Forty-second Street, and Seventh Avenue, is to be the secood highett sky-scraper in the
        city. Its summit will be 375
        of the Park Row building, which holds the eky-scraping record for
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1904-10-30/ed-1/?sp=54</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        LOFTY OFFICE BUILDINGS.
        The Tallest and the Narrowest Now
        Being Completed in This City.
        "Where will the audacity of the builder of sky
        scrapers stop?" Such a question is likely to
        arise in the mind of the most casual observer
        -is he walks about the city. Within the last few
        months several structures have been erected
        which eclipsed any of their predecessors in the
        boldness of their design, and just at the present
        time two buildings are being completed in the
        Wall Street district which would seem to mani
        fest an especial contempt for the laws of
        nature. Neither one has towers, and in
        this lass of office buildings one is the
        tallest in the world and the other is the
        nairowest. Because of their extreme type
        both present a most fantastic appearance. The
        first has a rear addition twelve stories higher
        than its front, and consequently looks as if
        ready to turn a somersault. The second is so
        thin that it resembles a gigantic soda cracker
        stuck up edgewise.
        Vet the builders of these skyscrapers declare
        that they are far safer than the dwarfish, three
        and four storied, old brick buildings that they
        overtower. To these men neither one of these
        buildings appears especially remarkable. Neither
        one represents by any means the limit to their
        daiing and skill. As one of them said:
        "If it were not for the law we could build
        them as tall as the Eiffel Tower, and that is
        11. 1 feet high, or a little more than GOO feet above
        the tallest skyscraper in New-York."
        Ncr is this audacity confined alone to the
        architect who plant? or the contractor who
        "takes tin- job." Every workman Mem im
        bued with this same characteristic. The riveter
        may be seen climbing about the top of a steel
        column some three hundred or more feet above
        the street as nimbly as a monkey. Now and
        then he will hang from that dizzy height with
        only a bolthead under the toe of one foot, and
        the other leg twisted around a crosspiece. Now
        and then some workmen will go travelling sky
        ward astraddle of a beam which is being hoisted
        by the derrick on top of the steel frame, and
        so unconcerned are they of danger that they
        light their pipes as they sail aloft.
        A comparison of some of the most recent sky
        scrap, is with a few of the earlier ones shows
        how much more audacious are the builders of
        to-. than those of a few years ago. As soon
        as the theory of the steel skeleton for tali struct
        ures was discovered, about twenty years ago,
        it was used to construct buildings of great
        size, which ware regarded at that time as mar
        vels of the builders' art. These structures,
        however, spread more than they towered. The
        ground area of some of them was tremendous,
        and oven at the present time a few of them sur
        pass all their more modern rivals in the size of
        tie p round they cover. The Produce Exchange,
        erected in ISM. which was the first large steel
        cage building erected In New-York, covers more
        land than any other ofP.ce- building in the city.
        Its total ground area is r.7..V<() feet. Its height,
        i M including its tower, is 130 feet. With the
        touir it is S-~> feet hie.h.
        In striking contrast with the Produce Ex
        rini-.c Building is the Trinity Building, now in
        tie loarse of construction at No. ill Broadway.
        it shows how the present day builder piles up
        bis structure, instead of spreading it out. Al
        though its topmost oflice floor is nearly two
        and a half times higher tlan that of the Prod
        uce Exchange, it stands on a plol having an
        r.verage width of 42 feet, or one-fifth :is wide
        as tie exchange. The Trinity Building is Jl
        stories high, an I, although it has only 11, .".us
        Fo.ua- reel of ground area, leys than one-fifth
        th.it if the Produce Xx change, it has a Boor area
        of •_'I:_V».SSf.-,t, or more than ui:e-h;iif that .f the
        exchange, which contains 401.430 square f t of
        floor.
        Tin building almost completed at No. C, Wall
        ■t., Whirl] runs through to Pine-st.. haa ::r. o.Tic.'
        floor VIA) feet abt.ve the street, or bighei than
        that of any ott r towerten building I.i the
        uorld. Tbis is the tw Mty-sixth Boor, and th.
        NEW-YORK TRIBUNE ILLUSTRATED SUPPLEMENT.
        RIDING ON IKON GITtDEU 300 FKET UP IN THE AIR.'
        Roof of the Washington Life Building in the background.
        roof above is .'{4(s feet from the curb. Oa the
        Wall-st. front the building is only fourteen
        IT Ui 1!i| NT»-:WN T »-:W TRINITY BUILDING AT NO. 11l BROADWAY
        i hi,- i he-,- l..riy iron mists the workmen climb like spiders.
        stories, or 2iV_> feet hish. yet. In spite of this
        handicap, the Hour area of 2Tr»,»>Ki feet la more
        than twenty times Its ground area. The floor
        area of the Produce Exchange is only a little
        more than eeven times the ground space.
        The Park Row Building, which with Its
        towers reaches a height of 3SO feet, higher taaa
        that attained by any other building in S v-
        York or elsewhere, has a floor area twenty-si.i
        times greater than that of the first story. Were
        the Produce Exchange to obtain such a propor
        tion, it would be necessary to pile upon the
        present bul ling three more of like size.
        In order to bring <>i t still more strongly th*
        flatness of the old and the si in. ness of the new
        style of office building, a few of the most striking
        examples of each are given in table form. Mo-:
        of the figures aro from ?peoi:ioa.t:ur-.d published
        In "The Record and Guide."
        OLD STVLK.
        Kwt Groun-1 F.^r
        Buildings. Stewart 7 U& 3.1.7.-0 55T..2.-.O
        1T..1M.0 Kxchanse". 7 »rjO 57.3.V. *.I
        Mutual Life....!.... 140 i*.-" 2*> 4»'.»
        lw-iiuujle 10 I*2 4O,7t*> 4NKW STYLE.
        Times BulMin*. 10an.l2H »22S 5.424 106.00©
        I'lnk of t/.,mm.r<<> JU S*> 10,4.'-) 3u»*.i«jO
        Whitehall -.I* 'i'> 4 11, «m
        Lord* Court l'j 270 15 "-V» 2S»"-"Broad Exchange '-1> 279 25.573 4T.V>««
        Kmpire 21 is3 13,97." 3H:'..475
        No. 42 Broadway 20 2*5 21.572 4^o.^'iO'
        Flatlron •_•■» 29<» 7 14»>.ikjO
        Trinity Building 1:1 -*9& 11.628 242,iik8
        I'aj-k Row 25 and ••'9 »312 1.1. aft) 34>.7r>*>
        >tan..ver Hank 23 and 24 32» 6.330 212.^(0
        No. Go Wall- st 14 and M 34« 13,400 275. 0U>
        •Without to*er.
        The flatiron form of structure, such as Is
        represented by the Fuller Building, in Twenty
        third-st., the Times Building. In Forty-see
        ond-st., which, with its tower, has a total height
        of 257 feet, which makes it rank second to the
        Park Row Building, and the Heaver Build!::?,
        at Beaver an 1 IVarl sts., is commonly regarded
        as the most scary type, but, as a matter of
        fact, it is the strongest. Its shape permits the
        best kind of bracing. In speaking of the Fuller
        Building. Paul Starrett. president of the George
        A. Fuller Company, who has his office on the
        eighteenth floor, said the other day:
        "Even in the heaviest gales 1 have never felt
        a tremor In this structure The wind has blown
        ninety miles in hour up here, and on one oc
        casion it knocked in some windows that had
        been put In temporarily before the building
        was finished, but it did not sway the steelwork
        one jot or tittle."
        Tut the upward tendency of the steel office
        building is not actuated so much by the ambi
        tion or pride of the maker as the business ne
        cessities of the owner. It is estimated that real
        estate on Manhattan Island is increasing in
        value at the rate of $100,000,000 a year. South
        at Central Park there are practically no vacant
        lots, and to the north they are disappearing at
        such a rate that such a builder as Charles T.
        Wills predicted recently that in fifteen years
        there will practically be none left. A compari-
        son of the vacant lots for the years li»«>«>. 1002
        and 1904 for the district east of Central Park.
        for example, will show how fast they are being
        built upon. In 1900 there were between Fifth
        ave.. Flfty-nlnth-sU Avenue B and •«i l -hun
        dred-and-twenty-flfth-st.. according t<» "The
        Record and Guide." 2,614 vacant avenue lots; in
        1902. 1.330; and this year, according to reports
        of the Buildings Department, there are only 700.
        The following percentages, taken in IMS by
        The Record and Guide." show the portion
        of space vacant in various Important West
        Side avenues: Central Park West. 31 per cent:
        Columbus-aye.. 7 per cent: Amaterdam-ave.. 17
        per cent; Broadway. 44 per cent; W»st End
        ave.. 27 per cent: Riverside Drive. 43 per
        cent. About one-half of this has since been built
        upon. Washington Heights, which up to the
        present time has been least developed. Is now
        building up fast, because of being made ac
        cessible to lower Manhattan by the subway.
        There were 211 vacant blocks in that region
        two years ago. according to 'The Record and
        Guide." and reports of the Buildings Department
        show that one-eighth of these have been built
        upon or will be built upon before the end of
        this year.
        The skyscrapers which are built on the sites
        of old buildings, however, are adding to the
        floor area of the city almost as fast as the
        buildings erected on vacant lots. In the year
        1903 101 buildings of nine stories or more were
        built in the district south of Leonard- at., which,
        according to Reginald P. Bolton. an engineer
        who ha-s planned the mechanical equipment of
        many of the .largest skyscrapers In the ity.
        has added ISO acres of floor area to that part
        of the city. This increase, it Is estimated. h;u»
        given 15 per cent more room, as the land area
        of this district is only 1.152 acres.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1904-10-02/ed-1/?sp=22</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        SOME VIE REMARKABLE NEW BUILDINGS tNNEW NEW NEWSKYSCRAPERS YORK YORKf
        L
        f SKYSCRAPERS GROWING BIGGER BIGGERMORE tsr fart s r r e p sr7t lt ANEWSTA ANEW A NEW STANDARD DARDSETFORTHEHO DARDSETFORTHEHOMORE SET FOR THE HO HOTELS H0MORE
        MORE LUXURIOUS AND MORE MORECOSTLY y ty TELS TELSOFTHEWORLDBYTHELATEST TELSOFTHEWORLDBYTHELATESTCOSTLY OFTHE WORLD BYTHE LATEST LATESTOF
        COSTLY THAN EVER BEFORE i r 3 OF THOSE BUILT IN NEW YORK
        n
        f
        of
        i lql i
        aulo 0
        There Tberewere were persons In this city not many manyyeanago many1earsago manyCeara
        yeanago Ceara ago when the upward race in sky skyecraper skyaper skyaoraper
        ecraper aper construction had hardly begun begunwho begunwho begunwho
        who predicted that the excessively tall tallbuildings taUbuildings tallbuildings
        buildings planned would not be successful successfuleither successfuleltheras euccesefuli
        i either eltheras as money making properties or as aspractical asi aspraotical
        i practical office structures structuresThe structuresTbelapeo structuresThe
        The Tbelapeo lapse of if time baa proved prol l that these thesepersons thesePeJIIonswere thesea
        a persons PeJIIonswere were mistaken Not only has the theskyscraper thekiscTaper theskyscraper
        skyscraper turned out to be a success inevery in ineverjr Ineyel7Particular
        every eyel7Particular particular except perhaps archi architecturally architexturally 1 1teCtumlly
        texturally but it has come to be an absolute absolutenecessity absoluteD absolutenecessity
        necessity D c Sslty
        Whether Who er with the improved facilities facilitiesfor facilitiesfor
        for rapid transit shortly to be available availableIn
        1 In the city lty and with the enlarging of the thearea thearea thei
        i g area of concentrated business activity that thathould thatllbouid thatshould
        should follow as a natural result the sky skyscraper skyncraper skyscraper
        scraper will continue to be as popular and andnecessary andneoessary andneoeeeary
        necessary as it is now remains to bo seen seenbut seenbut seenbut
        but In the opinion of many indicationspointto indications indicationspoint Indicationspoint
        point pointto to the conclusion that It willIa will willIn V1lIn
        In the buildings erected in the last two twoyears twoor twogears
        gears years or so including some of the notable notablejonia notableODM
        3 jonia sons ODM now in course of construction there therehas theroihM there1uishoen
        has 1uishoen been li e 1 a noticeable notlc nble increase over tho thoprevious thoI theprpiloue
        I previous p T1ous averago average In tho size and height heightj
        i j i of f the structures structures Where two years ago agov agothere agothere
        v there was but one Flatiron Building now nowthere nowthereare nowthere
        there thereare are are two or three all just as remark retnnrkt remarkiltble
        t iltble able In appearance as the one at Twenty lwent lwentthird
        third street streetBuiwhlle streetBlltwh1etho streetButwhlle
        Buiwhlle Blltwh1etho the office buildings have beengmsin been beengrowing beenJitrOWi
        JitrOWi growing bigger blgg r8nd and higher they have It ItVlaYeald Itct
        VlaYeald clald ct d been growing more costly the theYl theitiCrirdeea
        1 Yl itiCrirdeea creoMjUVCost i cost t 1 In many many instances being beingnotaVall bllngj beingnet
        j not notaVall a ata11proportlonate all proportionate to the Increase IncreaseIn
        In alze This has been true too in spite spiteof spltoof spiteof
        of the fact that tho general tendency re recently raciently rocently
        cently has been to minimize external art artin artID i iIn
        in the skyscraper and produce a building buildingEASY buildingBASY buildingi buildingBASY
        fll PfG7q 71P CaPYprGHr IPYFfIlTIfv yv u JH fON N Y
        with little expression of architectural architecturalform architecturalform architecturalform
        form formThe formThe formThe
        The Increased cost It is said resultsfrom results resultsfrom resultsrrom
        from the more elaborate and substantial substantialfinishing RubRtnntlalflnlsl subatantlalfinishing
        finishing flnlsl ng of the Interior and the more com complete complete complete
        plete equipment of the building with all allports allIIOrts allsorts
        ports of modem Improvements For instance in instance inIltanCt
        stance many of the recent skyscrapers skyscrapersbesides skyscrapersbesides kyscrapersbeflldl8
        besides having all the usual sanitary sanitaryequipments snnltaryI
        I equipments have Installed the vacuum vacuumsystem vacuumsystem vacuumI
        I system of sweeping sweepingI sweepingLines
        I I Lines of hose run from vacuum hydrants hydrantsin
        in the corridors Sweepers are attached attachedto
        j to the hone and by running them over theoffice the theoffice theoffice
        office rug the dirt is transferred in a twlnk twlnki twinkling
        i ling from the room hundreds of feet in ini
        i I the air to the basement basementThis bnsementI basementThis
        This is only one of the many modern modernconveniences modernconvenipnces modemconveniences
        I conveniences which the business man of oftoday oftoday oftoday
        today expects to find in these great build buildings hlllldthat buildingsbuildings
        ings ingsbuildings buildings that count their occupants occupantsby
        by h the thousand thousandthat that alone constitute in insome InlOme insome
        some cases an entire route for a letter car carrier carI carnor
        I rier nor and from which wl ch the dally mall is car carried carI carTied
        I Tied not by hand but by b the wagon loadThe load loadThe loadI
        I The skyscraper has always al Ys been a thorn thornin thornin
        in the flesh to the architect nrchitecttho the student studentof
        of the thebeaux beaux arts ar and the man who wants wantsfrankness wantsfrankneK8 wantsfrankness
        frankness of expression In his design designThese de8lgIlThese designThese
        These men complain that there is no noI noattempt
        I attempt in the American skyscraper to tomake toI tomake
        make its I appearance express its structure structureIt
        I It la a lie an uncouth lie from the founda foundation toundatlon foundation
        tion to the roof they the say fIa Seeking to toI
        I hide tho fact that It is built around a steel steelI steelframe
        I frame it simulates solid masonry masonryNearly Inl1lOnr Inl1lOnrI masonryNearly
        I Nearly Xearl all of them sin ln in tho nine wny wnythese wnythese waythese
        these architects say the buildings having havingthe havingthe havingthe
        the general appearance of n column with witha
        a heavy base a long Ion I central shaft and a adecorated adecorated adecorated
        decorated capital C What they would have haveJohn haeJohn haveJohn
        of the skyscraper If it really resl1 must be and andthey andthey andthey
        they admit that it must is i a franker ex expression oxpreeslon lXprl8slon
        pression of tho fact that then Is I beneath beneaththo benraththo beneaththe
        tho covering of stone and brick a frame frameof framoor frameof
        of steelThere steel steelThere teelThere
        There is I ono building in the city clt com completed COIIIplltf completecl
        pleted plltf 1 only about a a year eur ago which archi architects anhitec arrhttocts
        tects tec agree la I more successful Rucet jrul in thN thi re respect r rsped respect
        spect than most others It Is called callC t one oneof oneof oneof
        of the few reI successful ICl flll skyscrapers archi architecturally architecturally i itecturnlly
        tecturally regarded In the city cityIt elt cityIt i
        It Is tho Blair Building at Broad road street streetand streetand trretand
        and Exchange place A picture of it is isincluded I IIncludC isIncluded
        included 1 In the group above Its successlies success HUCCLSDlies I IICClMlies
        lies chiefly chien In tho fact that it does not simu simulate shnulate 111111late
        late solid masonry Its frame of steel Kteclis I steelis teelIs
        is not openly disclosed I but some of the thometal themetal themetal
        metal column are permitted to show in intho Intho inthe
        tho facade facadeshows fa facadeshows ade adeshow6
        But while some architects deplore the conventional con conventional convcntlonal
        ventional and what they cull inartistic inartistictrend Inartlstlotnmc inartistictrend
        trend in skyscraper architecture they the ad admit admit admit
        mit that it U I tho most notable and the themost themot themost
        most thoroughly American architecture of oftlm otthp ofthe
        the time and that it affords an opportunity opportunityfor opportunltfor
        for tho earning of the largest fees ever everobtained everoht everobtained
        obtained oht alnll by b architects in general practice practiceSo
        So far as IL the height of the office building buildingof
        of tho future is concerned there is II it in insaid II IIII1ld issaid
        said practically no limit below CO or 70 70stories 70torie 70stories
        stories torie imposed by byeconomical economical or structural structuralconsiderations IItructuralcon structuraleonsideratlmm
        considerations con icleratlonR All that will las lx necessary necessaryis nfCfI nr nrIR
        is a FUfllcient amount of space for tho foun foundations foundation foundatlons
        dations dationsTho dationThe datlonsiheowners
        The iheowners owners of the t hI buildings havehowover havehowoverfound haphowlverfOllnd havehoweverfound
        found that there is a limit imposed byIhn by bythn hytho
        thn sentimental nature of tho office oc occupant occllpant nocupant
        cupant and that there are few who earn earnpeople earoJllople rarehoopla
        to he higher than the buildings constructed constructedat
        at present It is not impossible though thoughthat thoughthat thoughthat
        that this objection may disappear In time timeThe tlmoTho timeThe
        The Hanover National Bank Building at atNassau atnssal atNassau
        Nassau nssal and Pine streets tho Beaver Build Building DulldInlt Building
        ing at Beaver and Spruce streets the Times TimesBuilding TlmlsBuilding TimesBuilding
        Building at Broadway and Fortysecond Fortysecondstreet FortICCOndtlllt
        street and tho Sixty Slxt Wall Street Build Building BuildIng Building
        ing now in course of construction are some somoof someof omoot
        of the th most notable structures of the last lastyear laltenr lastyear
        year enr or two twoThe twofI twofie
        The fI Hanover National Bank Building Is Unoted Isnotld Isnoted
        noted for the massiveness mai henlf of its It I structure structuretho structuetho structurethe
        tho characteristic charactlri tlc deplored by b many mnn archi architects arhItlct architects
        tects in view of its steel framo framoand and Its Itscostly Itllcot itscostly
        costly cot and elaborate interior furnishings furnishingsIt
        It Is I twentytwo tWlntyt 0 stories high and built builtmostly builtmo builtmostly
        mostly mo tly of granite graniteSome graniteSome graniteSome
        Some idea of Its massiveness ma lIhlnIRII can be got gotand gotI
        when It is said that each of the stones In the thecornice thecornice thecornice
        cornice at the eighteenth floor weighs weighsbetween weighsbetween weighsbetween
        between eighteen and twenty tons The Theinterior TheInterior Theinterior
        interior is finished in marble and bronze bronzeIt
        It t is said to beqne of tho most expensive expensiveoffice expen expensiveoffice lve lveoffice
        office buildings hulldlngslnthe in Inthe the world worldThe worldThe worldThe
        The Blair Building which Is of whitemnrble white whitemarble whitemorble
        marble IB seventeen eNiteen stories high and al almost almOllt almoat
        most equally elaborate In its interior fins fin finishings finIsl
        ishings ishingsTho Isl s ngR ngRTho ngsThe
        Tho Sixty Slxt Wall Street structure will bo boone boone beone
        one of the thegfants giants of the city clt probably probablyhlglier probablyhJgI probablyhigiierthan
        higiierthan hlglier hJgI er than any an any other office building ex exclusive exclusive exelusive
        clusive of of towers Its steel t el frame partly portlycovered partlylOverC partlycovered
        covered lOverC looms up Impressively from the theEast theFnst theEast
        East River and the Brooklyn rookln Bridgeand has hascaused baacaused hascaused
        caused a lot of wonder and comment commentIt
        It will ill bo built in two sections tlOnR and in inIts InIts inits
        Its architectural design will ill Illustrate lIIu trate the therecent therPClnt therecent
        recent trend toward simplicity in exterior exteriordesign exteriordesign x rior riordCIIlgn
        design The Wall WallstrCt street wing will be four fourteen fourI fourIteen fourteen
        teen stories high and the Pine street section sectiontwentysix sectiontwentyIx sectiontwentysix
        twentysix Its height will be 347 feet feetthe flltthe feetthe
        the Times Building and the Park Row Build Building BuildIng Buildlag
        ing each with a tower exceeding It by byseveral byslveml byseveral
        several feet feetTho rletTh feetThe
        The Th Beaver Bca ver Building and the Times Build Building BuildIng Buildlag
        ing like the Flatiron Building are notable notablefor notableror notableforlheir
        for forlheir their striking appearance and represent representpome representOrne representsome
        some of tho best attainments thus far In Ingetting Ingettln ingetting
        getting the greatest possible amount of offloor ort ortfloor c cfloor
        floor room out of the available foundaUotj foundaUotjspace foundaUo foundaUopaC foundatlospars
        space sparsThe spaceThe paC paCI
        I The changes In hotel construction lOn truction anrl anrlarchitecture an anII anarchitecture
        architecture arcl ltCture during tho last two or threij three threeyears
        II years have been much more pronounccdY pronounccdYthan pronounced pronollnccathan pronouncedthan
        than in tho skyscraper k cmpor A distinctly new newand newand newand
        and higher standard of construction and anddecoration anddNoratlon anddecoration
        decoration has been established establishedThis CRtnllllshodThis establishodThis
        This advance is represented chiefly in inthe inthe I
        the erection of the St Regis Hotel at Fifth Fifthavenue Fifthavenuo Fifthavenue
        avenue and Fiftyfifth street although althoughI
        the Hotel Astor at Seventh avenue and andFortyfourth andFortyfourth andFortyfourth
        Fortyfourth street Rdret and the Belmont and andthe andthe andthe
        the Brunswick in course of construction constructionare
        are factors In the change changeIt
        It was not until after the WaldorfAstoria WaldorfAstoriawas
        was wa opened that the builders of hotels and andtho andtho andthe
        tho men who run them learned that New NewYorkers NowYorkers FewYorkers
        Yorkers and tho American public In gen general peneral gonera
        eral era who come here wanted hotels whore whorethey wherethey Iwro Iwrothey
        they could get the best he t offered by the me metropolis mEttropoliK metropolis
        tropolis and that they were willing to pay paywell payell paywell
        well ell for it They The learned t also from the suc suecess success succriss
        cess cess of tho Waldorf that tho appearance appearanceof
        of the exterior of tho hotel and the interior interiorarrangements InteriorarrangementR interiorarrangements
        arrangements wnre much more potent potentfactors potentfactol8 potentfactors
        factors in Its success than had been sup supposed supposed UP UPpOIlN
        posed pOIlN before The St Regis Is eighteen eighteenstories IlghtlCnstories eighteenstories
        stories high massive mn8 1 ve and of gray limestone limestonebut IImestonnbut limestonebut
        but it will be exceeded in height by theHotel the theHotel theHotel
        Hotel Belmont and tho Brunswick BrunswickAs
        As Now York sets the fashion for the rest restof rllItof restof
        of the country In everything else sky skyscrapers sky skyscrapers kr krscrapers
        scrapers Included so also it is II predicted predictedby
        by men competent to speak that the ad advance nlvance advance
        vance in hotel construction and decoration decorationas
        as typified in the St Regis and the Hotel HotelAntor lIutelAtor HotelAstor
        Astor and other now hotels hot elK will shortly shortlystrlko shortlystrike shortlystrike
        strike a responsive chord in other large largecities largecltlell largecities
        cities as R occurred after the erection of oftho oftho ofthe
        tho Waldorf and that as 8 a result of what whathas whathM whathas
        has been done in New York there may maybe maybe maybe
        be exj expected ected another general upward step in inhotel IIIhotel inhotel
        hotel construction und equipment through throughout throughout
        out the th country countryThis countr countrThis countryThis
        This means also these the o men say that thatthere thnttherl thatthere
        there will probably be a corresponding correspondlnrle
        rise In the prices of what will bo rogardiM rogardiMIn
        In the future an the first class houses housoWhether hou6lWhethor housesWhether
        Whether the people generally enerall want till thosuperior tillsuperior thesuperior
        superior accommodations badly hnlll enough enoughto
        to pay tho increased bill as they undoubt undoubtedly undouhted undoubtedly
        edly ed will do in New OIW York Is something that thattlmo thattime thattime
        time only onl will 111 disclose discloseTHE cllscl080TilE discloseTilE
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1905-06-24/ed-1/?sp=24</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        ERA OF SKYSCRAPERS
        Skeleton Construction Began
        Seventeen Years Ago.
        PIONEER STRUCTURE

        THE MULTIPLE USES OF THE TALL
        BUILDINGS.

        First Built for Office Purposes Exclu
        sively, but Now for Homes,
        Schools and Factories.
        Written for Tho Star.
        Seventeeen years ago next Tuesday the
        work of construction was begun on the build
        ing which made the skyscraper possible.
        Within the next few weeks the work of
        tearing1 it down will be under way, and on
        the site will be erected a twenty-story office
        building at an estimated cost of a million
        and a half dollars.
        This pioneer structure, whose days are
        numbered. Is known as the Tower building,
        is located at 50 Broadway, New York, and
        is generally recognized among architects
        and constructing engineers as embodying
        the first radical application of a thorough
        going system of skeleton construction, the
        essential of the skyscraper.
        In some quarters It may still be held that
        this distinction does not rightfully belong
        to the Tower building. For many years
        after its construction a hot discussion was
        waged as to whether the Tower building
        was the pioneer, many claims for this honor
        being made by the architects of other build
        ings erected either shortly before or about
        the time that Bradford L. Gilbert, as archi
        tect, filed the plans for the Tower building.
        Of recent years, however, there has been
        little or no disputation concerning the
        Tower building's right to the distinction.
        This change was brought about largely by
        the careful and thorough investigation con
        ducted to settle this mooted Question by
        The Real Estate Record and Builders'
        Guide of New York city In 1898. This is
        what that publication, an authority broad
        ly recognized, had to say:
        New Light on Height of Skyscrapers.
        But though it has been highly practicable
        since the construction of the Tower build
        ing to run up buildings to heights undream
        ed of before, and there are structures vary
        ing from twenty-five to thirty stories in
        altitude above the surface, it is a note
        worthy fact that the average height of all
        buildings above the practical limit possible
        under the old system of construction Is far
        from being what one would naturally sup
        pose it to be after spending a day looking
        upward at the towering structures in the
        business centers of such cities as New
        York. Chicago, Philadelphia and Pittsburg.
        It was during the three years immediate
        ly prior to the outbreak of the war with
        Spain that there seemed to be a mania in
        New York for putting up record-breaking
        structures, in the point of altitude. Then
        were constructed the Park Row building,
        the highest office building in the world;
        the St. Paul building, almost as tall: the
        Empire building, and many others whose
        course of construction was followed pretty
        generally all over the country with much
        wonder and comment. During these three
        years In New York eighty-six buildings,
        ton stories and over In height were erect
        ed, and yet, notwithstanding the efforts on
        the part of many builders to put up ex
        ceedingly high buildings, the average height
        of each of the eighty-six buildings was only
        thirteen and a half stories.
        These three years saw the erection of the
        highest skyscrapers to date. Since then the
        tendency has been to erect buildings more
        on a level, as the figures for 190:1-4 and the
        present year up to May show. During this
        period there hsive been constructed In New
        York 111 buildings of all descriptions ten
        stories high and over In altitude, with an
        average height of a fraction over twelve
        stories, the fraction not being sufficient to
        permit of a garret of even small dimen
        sions.
        In this connection It Is worth noting that
        during these years only seven buildings
        above fifteen stories have been erected, of
        which four have sixteen, two eighteen and
        one twenty-six stories, respectively. From
        18St5 to ISA", Inclusive, fifteen buildings over
        fifteen stories In height were erected, divid
        ed as follows: One thirty, one twenty-six,
        one twenty-one, two twenty, one nineteen,
        five eighteen and four sixteen stories.
        This lessening of the heischt of sky
        scrapers is being explained In this fashion:
        Every story added to a building means In
        creased elevator service. That means, besides
        Increased cost of operation of the building,
        decreased income from renting, for more
        space must necessarily be given over to
        elevator shafts. Time has pretty thorough
        ly proved that a skyscraper is not the
        money-maker it was thought at first it
        would be. In fact, the owner of a sky
        scraper who makes 3 per cent on his in
        vestment should think himself lucky. So,
        It can readily be seen why the tendency of
        latter years has been to bring down the
        average height of skyscrapers below that
        of ten years ago.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87093029/1906-04-27/ed-1/?sp=7</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        ALLEST SKYSCRAPER
        IN THE WHOLE WORLD.
        Engineers, architects, and bulldem
        everywhere are Interested In the plana
        made public from New York for a
        skyscraper that will out skyscrape
        anything yet built. These plans were
        filed with the New York building de
        partment by Ernest Flagg, for the
        proposed Singer building. Nothing
        more radical has ever been attempted
        on either side of the ocean than Is
        embodied in the plans for this struc
        ture. The building is to be forty
        stories high and other buildings in New
        York and Chicago which now causa
        people to become stiff-necked looking
        up at them will, by comparison, appear
        small.
        Two of the tallest Chicago buildings,
        the Masonic Temple and the Majestic
        Theater, would be but one story high
        er than the Singer building, if on*
        was placed on top of the other. There
        will be 595 feet of the structure above
        ground and probably 125 feet of It
        below the street surface, bo that, all
        told, it will be ten feet longer than the
        mammoth* Amerlka, the .biggest steam
        ship afloat
        It was supposed the limit bad been
        reached in this style of structure, but
        it seems not Before long a fifty story
        pile may be expected to make slow go
        ing people gasp.
        While Chicago was the pioneer in the
        erection of tall buildings, it has tn
        the last few years been far outstrip
        ped by New York. The constantly in
        creasing population of Manhattan Isl
        and and the impossibility of increas
        ing the ground area for the accommo
        dation of the people made it neces
        sary to run the buildings higher and
        higher until it is impossible to tell
        when the limit will be reached.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1912-01-21/ed-1/?sp=61</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84023963/1913-11-14/ed-1/?sp=3</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        TALLEST BUILDING IN WORLD
        Proposed Structure Will Be Erected to
        House Goods for South and Cen
        tral American Trade.
        New York. Here is projected the
        tallest building in the world. It is
        still Ik embryo, but has progressed to
        the stage of blue print and architectu
        ral plan. The site has. not yet been
        selected, but if this great conception
        should gain the essential financial sup
        port of the parties interested Ameri
        can manufacturers who desire to es
        tablish their goods in South and Cen
        tral American markets, and the big
        Southern-American concerns who be
        lieve in the great opportunity of foster
        ing commercial relations between the
        wo Americas it will probably tower
        among the great structures arising
        around the new terminal of the New
        York Central.
        It is to be more than a commercial
        structure, however, for it is to house
        the club rooms and exhibition halls
        of the Pan-American States associa
        tion, which is now engaged in the" im
        portant task of introducing the two
        interests to one another.
        The design calls for a wonderful
        Spanish tower, pinnacled with red
        and gold, 900 feet in height. That is
        151 feet higher than the Woolworth,
        the present record holder among the
        world's tall buildings.
        Of course, the Eiffel Tower of Paris
        is higher yet, with its 304 meters, or
        approximately 1,000 feet. But the Eif
        fel tower is not either in form or pur
        pose a building; it is rather an engi
        neering demonstration along the lines
        of steel bridge construction, and beats
        about the same relation to a building
        proper that a fire escape or an exten
        sion ladder does to a staircase.
        The step ladder order of Manhat
        tan'sand that means the world's
        half-dozen champion skyscrapers will
        therefore line up as follows:
        Pan-American, 901 feet; Woolworth,
        750 feet; Metropolitan Life, 700 feet;
        Singer, 612 feet; Bankers' Trust, 539
        feet; Park Row, 3S2 feet.
        The estimated cost of this latest
        building designed by Francis H. Kim
        ball who is the architect of the City
        Investing building, the Manhattan Life
        and a dozen other of the colossal struc
        tures that have helped to make down
        town New York famous rather stuns
        the imagination, as do other figures
        mentioned in association with this
        project.
        The Pan-American building will call
        for some 21,000,000 cubic feet of build
        ing material of various kinds steel,
        granite, terra cotta, concrete, tiling,
        bronze, iron, glass, etc.
        Its estimated cost will be from $10,
        000,000 to $12,000,000.
        The main structure is to be 33 sto
        ries high, above which the tower, with
        its efflorescence of spires and cupolas
        in the general style of the Spanish re
        naissance, will soar to the altitude of
        901 feet.
        </text>
      </result>

    <!-- Using Query "New York High Rise Buildings", "New York Tall Buildings" -->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063730/1932-05-05/ed-1/?sp=6</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Now comes another “world's largest
        building.” It soon will begin to
        ris; from Manhattan bedrock to
        take its place as the central unit of
        Metropolitan Square—the $250,000,000 cul
        tural and entertainment project which popularly
        is called Radio City.
        At least ten buildings eventually will com
        prise the development, which is to house repre
        sentative groups of the theatrical, musical, mo
        tion picture and radio arts. The first three
        units to be built, however, will be a 66-story
        office and radio-studio building, an Interna
        tional Music Hall and 31-story office building,
        and a motion picture theatei.
        In height alone, the central building will lie
        418 feet less fhan the Empire btate huildinr
        1248 feet, but in gross area it will hate nearly
        three-quarters of a million more square feet than
        any other office structure in the world.
        The International Muiac Hall will be the
        world s largest theater, and has been designed
        to seat 6000 persons. I his and the motion
        picture theater, accommodating 4000. will cost
        $10,000,000.
        Ihe entire-development, which will cover
        nearly all of three square blocks along New
        ork s Fifth Avenue, will have four more of
        fice buildings, two of them of 45 stories each, a
        department store, underground traffic terminals
        and perhaps a new opera house.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1906-07-22/ed-1/?sp=18</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Sex cnty-five Millions for New Build
        ings on Manhattan,
        n- I!, nr> \lr\:iiiilrr llurwKuL
        Plans are drawn and contracts signed for the
        trectioi of over $75,001 000 worth of buildings
        •n Manhattan Island in the next twelve months.
        This is a huge figure, and the only way to realize
        tta magnitude is by comparison. The assessed
        realty values of the whole of the states of Ari
        zona, Nevada and Wyoming aggregate about
        fT9,000,000 $5,000,000 short of what New York
        Will spend for new buildings in one year. The
        area of Manhattan Island is 21.95 square miles;
        Chat of the three states above named Is 321,610
        square miles, or 14,652 times as large; yet in the
        ■mailer area there will be erected in one year
        •ew buildings of greater value than now stand
        Id those three states.
        For skyscrapers alone there will be spent
        about $-10,000,000, including those already partly
        constructed. Excluding all except those to be
        begun in the immediate future, the sum will be
        •bout $30,000,000. This is represented in nine
        teen buildings, whese total number of stories
        Will be 401 .and whose total height will be ap
        proximately 6.000 feet, or Just about as high as
        Mount Washington. They will have a total floor
        ■pace of 3,000,000 square feet, or 68% acres; this
        Is equivalent to the floor space of 800 three story
        •tty houses.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84038306/1906-11-21/ed-1/?sp=3</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Fifteen years ago, when the Mnson
        ic Temple, In Chicago, was built It
        was the tallest building In the world.
        It still holds Its place as the highest
        business structure in Chicago, though
        the limit has been outdone many times
        in New York. Today such has been
        the advance In sky-scraper engineer
        ing that New* York has now In course
        of construction a building that will be
        nearly twice as high as the Masonic
        Temple. The foundations for this new
        est sky-piercer,, which is to be 025 feet
        high above the sidewalk, and has forty
        one stories, are already in, and the
        work of piling the structure skyward
        has begun.
        To conceive a forty-one story build
        ing, with its roof -three times as high
        In air as the steeple of Trinity church,
        from which visitors formerly viewed
        New York, challenges the Imagination.
        This sky-scraper "limit" is being part
        ly remodeled from the fourteen-story
        Singer Building, and the eleven-story
        Bourne office building adjoining. It on
        Liberty street
        Only the Eiffel Tower, ofjnll struc
        tures reared by Ingenious men, rises
        to a greater height than will this forty
        one-story building. But the openwork
        Eiffel Tower Is an engineering freak,
        while the New' York sky-scraper will
        be the business home of a multitude of
        people.
        In the very block on Broadway
        where the workmen are beginning to
        rear this colossus, another equally won
        derful office building Is to rise, more
        roomy even than its companion. In- the
        Singer building alone, an army of 100,
        000 men could flud easy standing room
        on Its nine and one-half acres of floor
        space.
        The drawing reproduced herewith
        from the architects' working plans and
        designs does not convey, at first glance,
        an Idea of the ambitious scale on which
        Xew York's sky-scraper "limit" Is
        being erected. But everybody familiar
        with the downtown district of New
        York will recognize In the foreground,
        on the corner of Brondway and Liberty
        street the old Benedict building. This
        Is six stories high. Fifty years ago It
        was one of the tallest and finest build
        ings In New York. It Is now dwarfed
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030272/1913-03-30/ed-1/?sp=63</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>
      
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045774/1920-10-24/ed-1/?sp=52</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        n'T^HE artistic skyscraper" is the latest
        J inspiration of C. Ft. W. Nevinson,
        the British painter, and he is making
        preparations now to sail after months of
        work on "New York."
        "The skyscrapers are the most artistic
        things that the United States gives to the
        world," Mr. Nevinson declared at a private
        exhibition here recently of nearly 100 canvases
        depicting New York scenes. "The
        skyscraper is the architecture of to-day; it
        represents modern life and is always to be
        preferred from the artists' point of view to
        attempts to reproduce ancient Greek styles,
        which must expose their sham."
        In some the groat buildings begin at the
        bottom of the canvas and go up and out of
        it. In others he has the skyline laithfully
        reproduced and the remainder of the buildings
        on some imaginative foundation. The
        giddy heights and the bewildering immensity
        of which old Gotham is so proud are not lost
        in any detail in the artist's collection. The
        buildings are painted with high lights and
        Clear lines, which make their towering character
        more striking.
        "Art," says Mr. Nevinson, "triumphs in
        utility, and the most beautiful products of
        the modern world are a Rolls-Royce car and
        a skyscraper. They have been built for strict
        utility; their lines are perfect and they must
        appeal to the genuine artist. New York will
        be remembered for its introduction of the
        architecture of the skyscraper long after its
        people have been forgotten for other things."
        </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>

<!-- ***************************************************************************************** -->

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-daylight-saving</id>
    <results>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038411/1918-03-16/ed-1/?sp=15</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        DAYLIGHT SAVING
        TO GIVE WORKERS
        TIME FOR PLAY
        'hysicians Believe Move Will
        Do Much to Better the
        Health of Many
        Men who like the great outdoors.'
        ho like to leave the offices for a
        alk. a little fishing trip nnd a round
        f golf—to-day praised the passage 1
        t the daylight-saving bill by Con- j
        ress.
        Physicians here to-day also were j
        f the opinion that tho new sched- j
        le. to become effective Easter Sun
        ay, will do much for thd healUi j
        fa great number of workers who'
        or the first time will have a chance
        3 get out into the parks and fields,
        fter a day's work.
        Businessmen generally tli rough-
        out the city this afternoon declared
        that the changing of hours would
        be accomplished without interrupt
        ing or hurting trade. It was said
        that tho change would mean little
        or nothing to the larger mills ahd
        munitions plants, where three shifts
        of men now ure engaged in working
        throughout the twenty-four hours, j
        No difficulty will be experienced in
        trolley car schedules, it was said at
        the offices of the Harrisburg and
        'cross-river traction companies and
        the turning of the watch will do
        the trick. i
        Theaters, railroads and every bus-
        iness house in the city will operate
        according to the now schedule, and,
        therefore, it was pointed out, there
        can be 110 confusion after a man
        has once reset his watch.
        Summed up, Mr, Littlefleld says:
        "The bill provides tor an hour
        advance in standard time at 2
        o'clock a. in. on the last Sunday
        in .March of each yefcr and at
        a. m. the lust Sunday in October
        uie standard time shall be retarded
        one hour. Eleven countries have
        adopted the summer daylight sav-
        ing plan. The first was Germany,
        then Great Britain, France, Austria-
        Hungary, Italy, Sweden, Denmark,
        Norway, Holland, Portugal and Au-/
        stralla. London, England, saved
        200,000 tons of coal during a sum
        mer. In England in five and one
        half months $12,000,000 in coal '.vere
        saved, and In France $10,000,000. It
        is estimated that in the United States
        $10,000,000 can be saved in light
        bills. The hour of daylight con
        served by the proposed law can be
        used by industrial workers throug
        out America for gardening and agri
        cultural work. This will be a most
        important gain. We are sure of a
        great shortage in farm labor this
        summer and something must be done
        to offset the probable loss in pro
        duction of farm products. The hour
        saved for daylight every day in April.
        May, June, July, August, September
        and October will be of inestimable
        value in stimulating the dwellers in
        cities and towns to interest them
        selves in the production of garden
        truck."
        PASS DAYLIGHT
        SAVING BILL;
        AWAITS WILSON
        Clocks All Over Country Will
        Be Turned Ahead
        One Hour
        Wusliington, Mar. 16—The House
        of Representatives, by 252 to 40. yes
        terday passed the Senate daylight
        saving bill, under the terms of
        which, when it receives the signa
        ture of President Wilson, it'will be
        required that all the clocks in the
        United States be turned ahead one
        hour at 2 a. m. 011 Sunday, March
        31, and remain advanced one hour
        until 2 a. m. on the last Sunday in
        October.
        Under the bill parsed by the
        Senate the limit was, fixed as the
        last Sunday in September. The
        House amendment extending the
        daylight saving one month was
        adopted upon representations by-
        Five standard time zones for th
        United States will be fixed by the
        Government, according to the bill,
        and it is made mandatory upon the
        railroads to follow the standard
        time.
        By the passage of the bill, tho
        United States joins with England,
        France, Switzerland, Portugal and
        the three Scandinavian countries in
        adopting a method of economy and
        efficiency first taken by Germany
        during the early days of the war.
        Millions of tons .of coal have been
        saved in these countries, it was
        stated to the House to-day by the
        supporters of the measure, by the
        simple means of turning the clock
        ahead over a period of five or six
        months a year.
        England reports a saving of 12,-
        000,000 tons up to date. Several
        Representatives who espoused tha
        bill admitted that when it was first
        proposed they considered it silly.
        But, they said, when they came to
        examine its virtues they fell enthu
        siastically behind it.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1918-03-16/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        These charts show vividly how the daylight saving plan will give j
        everybody more "free hour#" of daylight. You've heard this: "Well,!
        there are just so many hours of daylight in a day and you can't change j
        'em." But wait?the daylight hours before your work-day itarts are
        so-called "wasted hours"?you ?leep them away or spend them getting
        ready to go to work. The daylight saving plan merely "shifts" an
        hour of daylight to the "free hours" after work, when you can use it.
        The tables is based on the average June day and the workday from
        8 to 5 includes an hour for lunch.
        Moving the Clock.
        The clock will be set forward one
        hour at 2 a. m., March SI, according
        to the House bill. At the same hour
        on October 27, the clock will be set
        back.
        The present standard time rones
        will remain in effect.
        Both changes will take place on
        Sunday mornings so that the least
        possible wrench may be given to
        the industrial fabric of the nation.
        But even at that on the railroads
        alone there will be some 1.000 pas
        senger trains and 5.000 trains run
        ning on the tracks when the change
        comes, and 1,698.SIS railroad clocks
        and watches must be set forward
        to keep traffic moving and prevent j together. At present In summer
        accidents. In 1883. however, a sim- j London closes as New York opens,
        ilar change from local to standard i More time for golf, amateur base
        time went into effect on 100,000 ball and tennis.
        miles of railroad without a single
        mishap.
        Benefits of Plan.
        The following benefits will be
        reaped by the daylight-saving plan:
        Saving of one to one and a half
        million tons of coal per year, ac
        cording to Fuel Administration es
        timates.
        Increased food production by sub
        urban gardeners.
        Less traffic accidents.
        Improvement in health of all the
        people. More fresh air. Women
        workers will return from work in
        daylight.
        Speeding up of freight transpor
        tation by giving extra hour at docks
        and terminals.
        New York and London Stock Ex
        changes will be open for one ho'
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030431/1918-03-24/ed-1/?sp=58</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Daylight Saving Is Simplicity Itself
        How Ben Franklin s Idea Conceived in 1784, Just Made Into Law Here, Will Affect
        Folks After Easter and Save Millions to the Nation
        10
        By WM. ARCHIBALD FERGUSON,
        Secretary of the National Daylight Sar
        ins Association.
        ON Ihc coming Apwl 1 more people
        in the United Slates will probably
        be April fool vietims than on any previ
        ous or future April 1, for Congress lias
        decreed that at 2 o'clock on the morning
        of March 31 the hands of the clock shall
        be turned forward one hour; in other
        words, the United States will then begin
        to live under the davlight saving plan,
        and doubtless thousands will forget to
        make the change.
        The daylight sating idea U almost as
        Id as the United States it-elf and our
        country can rightly claim the credit for
        all the many advantages which will act-rue
        from it, not only in this country bat also
        in those countries which anticipated the
        United Slates in its adoption, for it was
        Benjamin Pranklm who Iirst conceited
        the idea.
        Tor many years in England in the
        last century Sir William Willctt annually
        introduced his davlight sating bill in Par
        liament and annually the bill wa- de
        feated amid laughter and ridicule.
        In 1915 Germany tirst adopted the plan
        to speed np the war production and io
        benefit by the tremendous saving in fuel
        consumption. France and England and
        nil other European countries except Rus
        sia soon alter followed her example.
        Since its adoption in Europe, the.
        United State.-, Canada and Mexico have
        been out of harmony, so far as time was
        concerned, with European countries, to
        their loss not only in business, for the
        stock exchanges of Ixindon and Paris un
        der the new plan were closed before the
        exchanges of New York and I tost on were
        open, but also as regards the tremendous
        savings pos-ible in light bills, which, it
        is estimated, annually will run from V0,
        000,000 to $50,000,000 in the United
        Sfates alone.
        The plan has been ardently advocated
        in this country since May, Wlfi, by the
        Merchants Association of this city, cham
        bers of commerce of Boston, Rochester,
        Philadelphia, Chicago and Pittsburg, the
        United States Chamber of Commerce,
        Washington, D. C, and the National Day
        light Saving Association, of which Marcus
        M. Marks, former Borough President of
        Manhattan, is the president. Mr. Marks
        has often been called the '"'father of day
        light saving in this country."
        The chief benefits of the plan, as
        proved by the experience of England,
        France and other European countries
        where it has been in force, may be gen
        erally summarized under three heads:
        Eirst General health of all people
        benefited by reason of an added hour of
        daylight in the late afternoon, which has
        been and will be u-ed for outdoor recre
        ation and exercise.
        Second Increased production of food
        stuffs through the stimulating cultivation
        of home gardening.
        Third Money saved in lighting bills:
        each householder will burn artificial light
        one hour less each day, provided, of
        course, he continues his usual habits of
        retiring at night.
        The report of the summertime commit
        tee appointed by the British Parliament
        in September, 1!1G, to inquire into the
        social and economic results of the sum
        mertime act shows that the extra hour of
        dat light was generally ucd for the pur-po-e
        of outdoor recreation and pursuit's,
        and, in particular, for the cultivation of
        home gardening.
        The athletic dubs reported that the
        cricketers, bowlers, golfers and tennii
        players took full advantage of the extra
        hour of light, and swimming pools and
        playgrounds were utilized to full capac
        ity. Iu view of the national agitation last
        year, which is being renewed now, for
        the cultivation of home gardens to in
        crease the production of food the inaugu
        ration of the daylight saving plan iu this
        country will undoubtedly very greatly
        stimulate home gardening, particularly in
        the neighborhood of the great cities. In
        New York city alone there are 1,000.000
        daily commuters. Should only one-half
        of them use the extra hour of daylight
        which the plan will give in cultivating
        home gardens there will bo 3,000,000 extra
        hours utilized weekly in gardening and
        during the seven summer months in which
        the plan is in operation 2,000,000 days of
        extra work and time will be spent by
        these 500,000 commuters in the cultiva
        tion of gardens.
        This sating will he unitersal as every
        hou-eholder will u-e one hour les- of aili
        licial light daily under the new plan.
        Other additional benefits will be the re
        duction of traffic accidents due to Ici-cncd
        tran-poriation of pa'.sengers under arti
        ficial light, reduction of the danger of eye
        strain on account of the lessened amount
        of reading and work done under artiticial
        light and more lime for open air military
        drilling.
        The davlight sating hill as signed by
        President Wilson on March 19 provides
        lhat the plan shall go into effect at 2
        o'clock antemeridian time on Sunday
        morning, March 31, at which time clocks
        and watches, probably upon a signal
        flashed from the United States Naval
        Observatory at Washington will be
        turned ahead one hour. Comparatively
        very few individuals, unless by design,
        will be conscious w hen the change is
        made. "This hour was selected by reason
        of the fact that at 2 o'clock in the morn
        ing the number of railroad trains actually
        en route is smallest, and the number of
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88064305/1918-03-28/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=2</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87057262/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=7</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Every city in the country, every
        town and village, everything is in
        readiness for the new system, a sys
        tem that will save the nation thou
        sands of tons of coal daily as well as
        assisting the working man, the shop
        girl and the laboring clasa as well as
        the busy office man.
        What this plan means to the nation
        can be described in a few words. In
        the first place It means the conserva
        tion of the fuel supply. Secondly,-it
        gives the average man more time to
        devote to gardening, which In turn
        means a "bigger supply of food for the
        nation and, thirdly, it means a more
        healthy nation.
        The work of the masses will be done
        In daylight, where, heretofore, it was
        done In the dark a certain number of
        hours a day.
        The daylight saving plan will give
        the following daily advantages:
        One hour or more for outdoor rec
        reation. Recreation is a national as
        set, an immense force for health and
        moral well-being.
        Working mothers and fathers obtain
        an extra hour for outdoor play with
        their children, both summer and win
        ter.
        One hour less for bad lights in tene
        ments.
        Lessened eyestrain for workers and
        school children due to the use of artifi
        cial light.
        Smaller risk of accident in indus
        trial establishments, because there
        jwill he a light hour instead of a dark
        one at the end of the working day at
        ,tlie time of greatest fati-gue and most
        {frequent accidents.
        Lessened risk of accidents due to
        I transportation and traffic conditions,
        because the afternoon rush will fall in
        iduylight Instead of darkness,
        Working girls will be on the way
        home in the daylight instead of in the
        !dark in winter.
        Our last hour of sleep will be sound
        ier and more 'beneficial than it is un
        der present conditions, because there
        will be less light.
        General efficiency will, of course, be
        •increased by any improvement in the
        (health morals and social welfare of
        tiie workers and others.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030193/1918-03-30/ed-1/?sp=3</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        The programme is complets to-dsy
        for welcoming Amerlcs's first twenty-three.
        hour day with due dignity
        and ceremony. New York, which
        originated tha daylight aavlng move
        ment. will lead in the celebration.
        All clocks are to be puahed ahead
        one hour to-morrow morning. Tke
        hour from 2 lo J will he dropped, cut
        out as effectively aa If II never were.
        Thus I. ister Sunday becomes the
        llrst twenty-three-hour day In United
        Statea history.
        All railroad employees and marine
        nun on duty to-morrow at 2 A.
        will simply lake out their watches
        ,.nd push i io in uhead -no hour Offi
        cials huvo arranged achedulea to con
        form to the change No trains are
        scheduled to lea. New York between
        and 3 A M to-morrow, so no con
        fusion will arise. Milkmen may be
        a little late because milk trains ma
        no) have gained the lost hour by
        dnwn lo-morrow.
        It Is estimated the added hour of
        layllghl win save Ili'.x),ono In money
        and l.isai.ooo tons of ooal, It will also
        add W the Nation's food supply by
        giving garden, os Hie i ntra hour.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1918-03-31/ed-1/?sp=8</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Text of Daylight Saving Law
        An act to save daylight and to provide, standard time for the United
        Be it enacted by the Senate and
        United' States of America m. Congress -ossemDiea, mat, ior ine.pur-.
        pose of establishing the, standard time of the United States, the ter
        ritory of continental Umted States shall be divided .into five zones in
        the manner hereinafter provided. The standard time of the. first zone
        shall be based on the mean 'astronomical time of the second, .zone, on
        the.ninetieth degree; that of the third zone, on the one hundred and
        fifthdegree; that, of thefourth zone on .the one hundred and twentieth
        degree, ard that of the fifth zone, which shall include only Alaska, on
        the" one hundred and fiftieth' degree. That the limits of "each zone shall
        K AofmaA hv an nrtloi- nf thp Interstate Commerce Commission, having..
        regard for the convenience f commerce and the existing. jucc.tion J
        points and division point 'of common .carriers engaged in commerce-J
        between the several States' and. with foreign nations, ana sucn oruer
        'may be modified, from time to time. r
        o Tht within the resnective zones created under the" auth
        ority hereof Ihe standard time of the
        oi all common earners rengagca in- commerce ikhvbm -mo kici
        States or between a State and any of the Territories of the United
        State, or'bftween a State or thtfrTerritory of Alaska and any of the,
        insular possessions ottlie United States orany lereim countrytflrf
        all statutes; orders, rules, and regulations relating, io the time,of,-per-;
        formance of any act by anyof ficer or .department of the United States,
        whether in the legislative, executive, or, judicial branches of the Gov
        ernment, or relating to the tinre within which any rights shall accrue
        or determine, or within which any act shall or shall not be performed
        by-any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States, it shall
        he Understood and intended that the time shall be the United States
        standard, time of the zone within which the act is toibe performed.
        Sec? 3. ThaJ; "at two" o'clock antemeridian of the last Sunday inj
        JIarch of .each year.jhe standard time oi cacn zone snail De advanced
        one hour, and at two o'clock antemeridian of the last Sunday in
        October in each year the standard time of each zone shall, by the re
        tarding of one hour,-be returned to the mean astronomical time of the
        degree of longitude governing said zone, so that between the last Sun
        day in March at two o'clock antemeridian and the last Sunday in Octo
        ber at two o'clock' antemeridian in each year the standard time in each
        zone shall be one hour in advance of the mean astronomical time of the
        degree of longitude governing each zone, respectively.
        Sec. 4. That the standard time of the first zone shall be known
        and designated as United States. Eastern Time: that 6f the second zone
        shall be known and Designated as United States Standard Central
        Time; that of the.third zone shall be Known and designated as United'
        States Standard Mountain Time; that of the fourth zone shall be
        known and designated as United States Standard Pacific Time; and
        that of the fifth, zone shall be known and designated as United States
        Alaska Time
        Sec; 5. That, all Acts and parts of Acts in conflict herewith are
        hereby, repealed.
        Approved March 19, 1918.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87057262/1918-04-01/ed-1/?sp=5</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Keoktik observed the daylight sav
        ing law Sunday morning by turning
        the clocks ahead one hour. And every
        The earth Is approximately 24,000
        miles around. It makes a full turn in
        twenty-four hours, or travels at the.
        rate of say one thousand miles per
        hour. We poor mortals, clinging to
        the earth as best we can are being
        whirled around at this excessive rate
        of speed. We are going some. Yet
        Sunday morning at 2 o'clock, when the
        clocks were changed, we made an ex
        tra jump of a thousand miles in our
        mad race. Did you notice the change?
        An hour a day gained has its dark
        side as well as its light. For instance
        rent becomes due an hour sooner. We
        are one hour nearer the grave. Life
        and fire insurance expires one hour
        sooner. The thirst parlors in the dry
        towns close one hour earlier. Weeds
        have an exta hour to grow in the gar
        den.
        High noon isn't as high now as It
        was before and midnight is not quite
        so mid.
        The profiteer liaB now another ex
        cuse for raising the price. He can
        ?,mA"°?/"*
        ay
        a®c°,Vnt
        ii OT 3 TV*
        time, etc. etc."
        it is anticipated that this flag. Pledge to the flag. Flag drill.
        will out-rival all others in se- The centennial program as well as
        determined. Whoever centennial celebration, and is circular program, "Planting the Cen-
        the mh 0f
        J. 1- ithe man who stole the chickens. (anniversary of the enabling act of been much in demand as a patriotic
        Bloodless people, thin, anemic people,
        on Aoril 18, 1818, the state speaker during the past few-months, ver H. Cossart, deceased, was filed
        iarge anfl appreciative the.daily program to include salute *t
        schools, is making every effort for simple flag drill to be found in the
        children throughout the school journals.
        to assist in the observance of Planting the Centennial Tree—A
        to arrange and give a suit- teacher, which can be made a very
        centennial and patriotic program interesting part of the program.
        April, which is the: States Attorney Earl W. Wood has,
        congress, on April 18
        centennial commission has
        mended that April 18. 1918, be one to make addresses, including Still
        of the dates to be observed this year,
        1
        become more an l' exercises to be held in the rural dis- yet finds time to give many hours to
        of «sh" is^ie cry utter- tricts in the afternoon or evening, the enlightment of the people of his
        hv ^rLu
        J^he TLeszei^n^ rl I while in the larger schools teachers vicinity along patriotic lines.
        If fdltlom of which have
        evening at
        of the change in
        The biggest change comes around
        midnight. What used to be today Is
        now tomorrow.
        Wonder if a fellow died at 2:30 a.
        m., Sunday, if the life insurance com
        pany couldn't avoid payment by claim
        ing there was no such time?
        A Keokuk policeman on the night
        force left the station one minutes be
        fore two Sunday morning and walked
        city and village in the United States I f^pidly to the union depot He got
        did the same thing. Whatever time it
        is now, it was an hour earlier a day
        ago. One hour of Sunday morning
        must be accounted for somehow, some
        where. Who's got It?
        there at 3:10, an hour and fifteen min
        utes for eight blocks.
        A traveling man who arrived In Keo
        kuk at 2 o'clock Sunday morning and
        walked up the hill to the hotel, found
        that it took him over an hour to make
        the trip. He wiped the perspiration
        from his face and said to the hotel
        clerk: "Whew, I knew that was some
        hill I was climlbing, but I didn't realize
        it was that long."
        If a fire had broken'out in the Estes
        house at 2 o'clock Sunday morning, it
        would have taJcen the department an
        hour to get there. By that time the
        •fire would be beyond control. But it
        didn't.
        Children whose bed time has been
        8:30 o'clock, will have to go to bed
        before it gets dark these evenings.
        That's tough on the kids, but war is
        war.
        Easter Sunday of 1918 can always
        be remembered as having but twenty
        three hours. We used to think Decem
        ber 2,1 was the shortest day of the
        year, but the war has changed many
        things and now Easter is the shortest.
        If shoving the clock ahead one hour
        is such a good thing, why not go a
        little further and shove the calendar
        ahead one month. Why not tear off
        April altogether and have May right
        now, thus avoiding the April show
        ers and have fresh vegetables and
        warmer weather right away? Or go a
        little further and shove the whole
        year ahead. That might see the end
        of the war six months behind. Good
        scheme for somebody with plenty of
        spare time to figure out and suggest
        to Washington.
        Prisoners whose sentences expire
        before October 31, when the clock
        will be pushed back again, have bad
        their sentences reduced by one hour,
        'by the pushing ahead of the clock.
        </text>
      </result>

      <!-- Using Queries "Daylight saving in America", "Daylight Time Change"-->
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85035720/1923-04-28/ed-2/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Daylight saving time for the 1323
        season begins tomorrow morning at
        2 o'clock. Therefore it is important
        that you remember to set your
        watches ahead one hour before re
        tiring tonight. More than 350 cities
        and towns in the United States have
        adopted Daylight saving ordinances
        or resolutions making daylight sav
        ing time the standard time in their
        municipalities from May 29 to
        September 30.
        Although the clocks in the various
        municipalities will point to the day
        light time, railroad clocks will con
        tinue to show eastern standard time.
        However, the train used by com
        muters have been set ahead one
        hour so that they conform with day
        light saving time, although operat
        ing on standard schedule. When
        reading a time table it is necessary
        to add one hour to the time shown
        in order to have the time table con
        form with daylight saving time.
        The various churches of the city
        will begin their services tomorrow
        in accordance with the daylight sav
        ing schedule and the schools on
        Monday morning will open on day
        light saving time. Factories, offices
        and amusements will also be operat
        ed unde- the daylight saving sched
        ule.
        Among the towns and municipali
        ties In the vicinity that have adopted
        daylight saving are: Perth Amboy,
        South Amboy, Tottenville, New
        Brunswick, Metuchcn, Kevport.
        Matawan, Carteret, and Wood .ridge.
        Commuters from this city to New
        York using the trains of the Central
        and Pennsylvania which operate over
        the tracks of the New York and
        Long Branch railroad will find
        several changes in the lime of trains
        beginning Monday morning. One of
        the most important of these is that
        affecting the Central express leav
        ••‘O V«v,r tui i'cw AiniV CctUll
        morning at 8:13 o'clock. Beginning
        Monday morning this train will leave
        here at 8:25 daylight saving time
        and will arrive in New York at 9:20.
        For many years this train ran on the
        above schedule, but about a year
        ago commuters from this city, Lake
        wood and Red Bank petitioned that
        the train be set ahead. The change
        did not prove popular however, and
        the train has been replaced on the
        original schedule.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86074065/1919-10-29/ed-1/?sp=2</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        DAYLIGHT SAVING
        IS NOW NO MORE
        Unpopular Law Caused Over
        s riding of President’s Veto
        By Congress.
        At midnight Sunday the hands of
        clocks throughout the United States
        were set back one hour. With this
        act is- written the final chapter in
        the history of the Daylight Saving
        law as offectinR hours of work and
        rest in this country.
        The law dies by action of Congress
        at the overwhelming demand of
        farmer and minor interests and with
        protests from the cities and indus
        trial centers. To enforce its will,
        Congress was forced to override the
        views and judgment of President
        Wilson and to repeal the law in the
        face of the President’s veto.
        .me me oi me uayugni saving
        law was short and stormy. Enacted
        March 19, 1918, as a war measure,
        the law was provided for pushing a
        head the clock one hour on the last
        Sunday in March and returning it
        one hour on the last Sunday in Oc
        tober. It provided, also for five zones
        of standard time in the United
        States to govern the movement of
        all common carriers engaged in in
        terstate commerce. This feature of
        the law has not been changed.
        Almost from the hour the Daylight
        Saving Law went into effect com
        plaints arose against it. The coal
        miner declared it took him from his
        bed before sunrise in order to get to
        the mine at work hour, the farmer
        and trucker insisted that it sent
        them into their harvest, fields and
        truck patches when the dew was
        still on the fields and an hour or
        more was lost waiting for the dew to
        dry under the sun.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1941-06-21/ed-1/?sp=11</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Daylight saving exists today in
        some of the great cities of the
        Middle West, but speaking by
        and large, it does not hold in
        Da\ r,
        SavimC- i
        the States of the West and
        South, but is confined largely to
        the New England States and
        the Middle Atlantic States.
        In England daylight saving
        has been in operation all during
        the war, and more recently, the
        system was advanced so as to
        save not one hour, but two hours
        of sunlight. This enables the
        British not only to conserve fuel
        ant power, but makes the black
        out at night, which blankets the
        country, more endurable.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88084272/1919-07-14/ed-1/?sp=6</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1919-03-30/ed-2/?sp=22</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        The clocks of tho nation movod for
        ward onc hour at 2 this morning and
        the daylight saving plan was put into
        opcration for the fiecond auccessive
        year in Amcrica. Until October "6,
        when clocks will bo Bct back ono hour
        again. citizor.s of the rrpublic will llve
        sixty minutea ahead of nctual time.
        Farmers diasatiafted with tho work
        ing of the daylight saving eystem made
        a determined attempt to kill tho law
        eome montha ago and Its abolition waa
        included in tho agrieultural approprla*
        tion bill. This wm held up by the
        Senate fUibaater and the farmers wero
        thwarted,
        On the other hand, workera in in
        *8u?try have wclcomed tho plan, So en
        thueiaBtic are tho cltixens of Detrolt,
        Pontiac and Alpena, Mich., over the
        ayatem, that ofter trylng daylight aav
        ing last year ptoy moved thoir elocka
        ahead permanently and havo adopted
        F-a?tern ctandard llme in preference to
        Central, time, which they hltherto
        uacd.
        </text>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>

  <!-- ***************************************************************************************** -->

  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-halleys-comet</id>
    <results>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn95047417/1909-09-03/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        htnetonUji4U Waahtngton W j Hl ive Iveuptil veuntllnext veuntllnextprinC until next nextspring nextspring
        spring you au are W gotf tt1ritnHl Vex O witness oneot oneotthe one ot otthe ofthe
        the most magaifiaeatihte mAgniHoeats rhts bJ the thehven thehvenbe heavens heavenshas heavenshas
        has ever dleoleeed befltfe t your out eyes eyessaid ey eyaid eyessaid
        said a well knew mejs ttrelaber er of the aatro aatroaomical utroaomlcal aatroaomical
        aomical force at th tH tJaited q nitad ted States nairal na nayal nayalob
        yal yalob observatory tvator this aJtemoon moon Hal Halleya HalJe11 Halelays
        lays oomet ceaaes c pvjjJF eacein enoe Ol in a allf allftim life lifetime lifetime
        time and many ptosfiv are hrr born live liveand liveand liveand
        and dlewltboutt die without ever oJchlng bing hingarUmp hingarUmpof a glimpse glimpseof
        of its marvelous d dasILJnire fire across the thaakI theskies theskies
        skies akI It was last aew In m 1886 and few fewpersoBS fewperaou fewperrssonnss
        persoBS now alive e ela say they have haveever haveever haveThe
        ever perrssonnss witnessed now it itThe o
        The astronomical a ifOJfld Is a now on t twatch tht thtwatch thldwatch
        watch and huge refraJUng Nt and reflecting reflect reflecting reflecting
        ing telescopes are Ir trained wed upon the theheaveaa theheay8AI theheavens
        heavens front saaay pelats ta on the earth earthin
        in a common effort Ror ort U eeate te the comet cometwhich cometwhloh cometwhich
        which is approaching the earth at a atoraifflc ateralmc ateraitZc
        toraifflc rate There tJ a a friendly rival rivalry rivalry rivalry
        ry to see which will be the first to pick pickup pickup pickup
        up the comet with their mirrors mirrorsThe MirrorsThe tairrorsThe
        The comet in itafulJ its 101 f iU refulgence is isnot lanot isnot
        not due until 1910 1 10 bu but by yr spring it will willprobably willprobably willprobably
        probably be near nMti enough 1 ugh to be bevisible bevisible bevisible
        visible to the naked eye 1L In the past pastit t tit
        it has haslpanned spanned the heavens hHV almost from fromhorizon from fromhorizon fromhorizon
        horizon to horizon aoverin covering as much muchas
        as 100 degrees of ofoelU Celestial J territory and andstanding andltandln andstanding
        standing out like a greet t living thing ttiingof ttiingofre of offire ofare
        fire re It is now somewhere off of ff in space spacebut spaoebat e pacebut
        but not notyat yet visible to astronomers They Theyconfidently Theyconfidently The Theconfidently
        confidently expect someone IOml Re to pick ft ftup itup It Itup
        up before the tn end of ot1909 J909 and after afterthat afterthat afterthat
        that it will increase in splendor afilendor lndor and size sizeuntil sizeuntil sizeuntil
        until It reaches Its nearest nea t approach to tothe toth tothe
        the th earth e rtb sometime next spring after afterwhich afterwhich afterwhich
        which it will disappear dl ppear not ot toi to be eseen eseenagain seen seenagaln seenagain
        again In 75 years yearsHalleys yearsHalley
        Halleys comet ham been visiting viaitin the thevicinity thevloinlty thevicinity
        vicinity of the earth ever since 100 l O0 K or
        600 years before Chriat u said the as astronomer astronomer astronomer
        tronomer Halley was an Englishman Englishmanwhose Englishmanwhose Englishmanwhose
        whose name was given to the comet cometbecause cometbecaUlf cometbecause
        because be was the first to announce announcethat announaethat announcethat
        that this particular comet came near the theearth theearLh theearth
        earth at regular period once every 75 75years 76y 75ears
        years y ears r He went over the tit records and andby andI andby
        I by a series sert sertesof of computatiosifound und whatbad what whatbad whath
        bad h d previously been regarded as a arill se series asriea
        rill of different comets tgas s nothing nothingmac nothing nothingthismp
        mac tbaB the sanutdoiRt soma rna 4Qdt andthw andthwthis and that thattbJB thatis
        this thismp is t1 the e most magnificent magn fluent of o t th them lt1 all alloame aUoame allosme
        oame around regularly once every eyer 75 75years 75years
        years 8110 That was during the thelatter latter part partof partof t tof
        of the eighteenth century and Halley Halleyannounced HaUeyannounced Halleyannounced
        announced that this comet would next nextappear nextappear nextappear
        appear in 1863 He never lived to see seeit leeIt seeIt
        it come but his bl successors found that thathis thatbls thathis
        his prediction pre t leUon came true4The true trueThe trueITho
        The comets Bovontyflveyer soventy flveyear jour journoy joutney journay
        nay will bring it toward us near enough enoughfor
        for it tobeseon to be seen early olrl in 1910 It has hasnever liunever hasnever
        never before been photographed be beeause belAale beeeauee
        eause photography was invented after
        1895 Neiyier Net ber 8r has the spectroscope Ipect pe been beenused beenUHd beenused
        used upon u this comet this being anotb another
        er new invention The telegraph is an another anotber another
        other facility not available in 1816 1 and andthere andthere nd ndthere
        there was at that time time nothing like ilk the thegreat thereat thegreat
        great reat telescopic lenses of today tod y or the thegreat theIreat theneat
        great neat 40 inch refractive telescope at the theYerkes th thYorb theYerkes
        Yerkes Observatory 60 miles milMnorthweet milMnorthweetof northwest northwestof
        of Chicago ChicagoWitb
        41 With all these facilities astronomers astronomerswill trnomerswill
        will this time work in harmony and a acommittee acommittee acommittee
        committee on comets was some time timereport timeBlCO timeago
        ago formed for the pu purpose e of report reports reporting
        ing in a plan lan fOtoblervlngHaJletoot fOtoblervlngHaJletootThis for observing Halleysoornt HalleysoorntThis s oomet oometsession
        This This committee reported at thiBA th JAM1 JAM1lesalon al alsession
        session of the Astronomical and andAltt andAlttp Astro Astrophysical Aetrophysical
        physical p ylc l Society of America at theYerkee the theYerkes theYerkH
        Yerkes Observatory on Lake Geneva GenevaWis a aWI GeaevaWI
        WI L
        WisA A series of telescopic photographs photographswill p e apj1 apj1will
        will be taken tak n at the Lick Yerka Navat Naval Na Naval
        val and other observatories o in this coup country oopat couptry
        t try and all the large observatories observatoriesaboard obReryatoriHa6oaid observatoriesaboard
        aboard including those at Berlin Vim Vienna Vftnna Vimnap
        na nap Paris and andGreonwlch Greenwich We W want antto anttolet to toget toget
        get a long series l ri88 of actual telescopic tk telescopicphotograph Ulawomophotograph o t8 t8pho
        photograph pho ph of ofibi this comet on onItscoming onItscomingcruise Its I coming comingcruise oomfn oomfncruise
        cruise through th urb Jh the heavens The b cornet D t
        will 111 first be picked up somewhere on in inspace InI inspace
        space I ce by some photographic teJesedbe teJesedbeWe t ewe e ew
        w We think tbl ke we know just about aboutwhere where the thecomet thecomet thecomet
        comet will make its debut but cant cantyet eanttet cantyet
        yet et see It it The moment it is found the thenews thenen thenews
        news will be flashed around the worldThere worldTbere world worldThere
        There will be no trouble seeing Inglt Ingltwith it itwith Itwith
        with the naked eye It will illuminate illuminatethe Ulumlnatetbebeavenlr
        the tbebeavenlr heavens We have some early Chi Chinese Chinese CMflee
        nese prints representing repre enUng it u a golden goldendragon loldendragon goldendragon
        dragon of the heaven It will make a atremendous atremendoullpluh atremendous
        tremendous tremendoullpluh splash of fire After it once oncecomes oncecornea oncecomes
        comes and goes goealt It will shoot away awa from fromthe frenathe fromthe
        the earth going aa far away as Neptaae Neptaaethe N eptuaethe
        the most distant of the pladets passing patsingall InJt InJtaU
        all of the other planets cnroute iaclud iacludIIw tocludlog BCKW BCKWIng
        log Uranus Saturn turn Jupiter and Mars MarsWe ManWe MareWe
        We have calculated that Halley Halleyscomet HalleyCOlBtt Rallayscomet
        comet U now within the orbit ol l Joai Joait Ju Jutel Juter
        t tel raaid aaJd the astronomer and broth brothing ilruahInr is rush rushlog
        log toward the orbit of the earth eart atte atterate at the tberate therate
        rate of a million mile mU a day dayAa dayAJafaint dayAs
        Aa AJafaint a faint BebuHis object tntHGOMtjI tntHGOMtjIItIoII intlwcoest4kdoe in the COM Ul Ulktfoa
        ktfoa Orion it will 111 no doubt be pfeked pfekedup ed edup
        up la a few weeks Celestial Cele Celeetiatraphy Lal Lalaaph beSed beSedup jNietog jNietoglaphy
        laphy few H tt already located in ttftUlesB ttftUlesBspate t11s t11srpae t ttQ
        spate f fsk acbeyeod bey d tls tie evWtuiaf vision a l tJMrt tJMrtte tleritlelrtdebateteeespte t
        debateteeespte te ieeepie I reseuels neearea As Asenter I ifee ifeeenter tJteI
        I fMt enter teto the orbit ef efMB fit r r1tIt ar ara
        a a 1tIt wftt r brlirhter br hterde hterderagi 1 1t
        ragi MB t ft beeoftie 80 er vMIbto titite tt ttBMet tie tieIpICta to toktheinsttk
        BMet tpectattilir IpICta llr ofejeet ofejeetrtteftway NJttt1r1
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058179/1910-02-05/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Halley's Comet to Wrap
        Its Tail Around
        This Sphere
        New York, Feb. 1. Camilla
        Flammarion, the French as
        tronomer, in a letter published
        here today, says that the vapo
        rous tail of Halley's comet will
        onvelope the earth on May 19.
        "For several hours," he says,
        "we will be immersed in the
        gaseous caudal appendages
        whose chemical constitution is
        still little known. The comet
        will pass directly between the
        sun and the earth at 2 o'clock
        in the morning of May 19. At
        that hour the Pacific ocean will
        be in full daylight, while in
        France it will be night.
        Little danger may be expect
        ed, however, for the tail will
        probably be so rarified as to be
        inoffensive.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1910-02-08/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>0/rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058398/1910-02-09/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87076843/1910-04-08/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        Mlany questions have been asked
        regarding the great comet that Is ex
        pected to be nearest the earth on
        May 17, and the following questions
        and answers were among those asked
        and answered by Rev. Fr. Hllllg of
        Toledo, and published in the Blade:
        When will we be nearest to the
        comet?
        On May 18, about 8 p. m., standard.
        The head of the comet will then be
        about 12.000,000 miles away from us,
        that Is about half the distance of
        Venus from the earth when the two
        are at their nearest approach. There
        will be a transit or tho comet across
        the sun's disc, because sun, comet
        and earth will then be in a straight
        line. The comet's tall will then
        brush over the earth's face provided
        the tall be over 12,000,000 miles long
        and half a million miles across at
        die earth's distance.
        What will happen when we collide
        with the comet's tall?
        Nothing In particular! There Is
        as little danger in that collision as
        there Is In colliding with the odorl
        ferlous particles emanating from the
        highly perfumed dress of a person
        that has crossed the sidewalk a few
        seconds before you arrive on that
        spot. The matter of the comet's tall
        is thinner than, .the residue of air
        contained In a globe after exhausting
        it witb. the most efficient air pump.
        Even if tho cometary matter were
        the most poisonous gas some of It
        13 highly poisonous cyanogen It
        could not hurt us, firstly, because It
        could hardly descend through our
        dense atmospheric envelope of 80
        and more miles thickness, and, sec
        ondly, because it would be diluted in
        the air so as to become absolutely
        Harmless.
        Will the fact that we pass through
        the tall be noticed at all?
        Perhaps and perhaps not. The
        earth has passed through a comet's
        tall on one or two former occasions
        without any sensible effect. The
        most that we may anticipate Is a pe
        culiar luminosity of .the sky on the
        evening of May 18, or perhaps a me
        teoric shower. However, this predic
        tion has less than half the probabil
        ity with which the weather-man an
        nounces his probable showers.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058140/1910-04-19/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
         A great deal of Interest IN being taken
        in the comet in Salt Luke and there
        has been serious discussion of the re
        port from several more or less proml
        nent astronomers that the earth will be
        Iu danger on May 18 when it passes
        through the tail of the comet
        On that date the comet will be only
        10000000 miles away from the earth
        reaching Its closest proximity to this
        planet Professor Frost of the Yerkes
        observatory has found through ex
        periments that the comet shows pre
        dominant elements of sunlight in the
        spectroscope This he says shows the
        absence of the dangerous gases that
        were present when the experimnts
        were made last Januaryand this leads
        him to believe there Is no danger to
        the earth on May IS
        Jstftnfomira who save studied the
        history of the comet think the chances
        for a brilliant display when it reaches
        the western sky at night are good
        They point out that at the time of its
        appearance in 1835 there were portions
        of its orbit which showed no tail
        Diagram slums the path of Hiillejrs
        comet through the Molar system and i
        the number of years It requires to make
        the trip from poiut to point
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88084272/1910-04-20/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn95079246/1910-04-29/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        HALLEYS COMET.
        Size.
        1,000,000 times larger than the
        earth.
        Speed.
        Millions upon millions of miles a
        day.
        Character.
        The comet is composed of three
        parts?nucleus, head an tail. The
        head is of the same composition as
        the tail, only denser. The head is
        so transparent that stars can be
        seen shining through it. Nothing
        is known of the composition of the
        nucleus.
        The Tail.
        It is composed of gas and minute
        particles of metal not unlike dust.
        Should the tail be long enough,
        when, on May 18th, the comet cuts
        through the plane of the earth, to
        reach the earth, the effect would be
        a fine display of luminous vapor.
        Time or Passage.
        Between 7:30 and 8:30 on the
        evening of May 18th the comet will
        pass between the earth and the
        sun. As the sun sets in Virginia
        on that date at 7:15, the World
        Almanac says it cannot be witness?
        ed in this state, but might be seen
        from California, Hawaii, Philip?
        pines and Japan, although it may
        be possible that at that time it will
        not be able to be seen even with
        the telescope.
        Distance.
        At the time the comet passes
        through the plane of the earth it
        will be 78,360,000 miles from the
        sun, 14,640,000 miles from the
        earth, and the tail, which always
        streams away from the sun, would
        have to be more than 14,640,000
        miles long to envelop the earth,
        and it may not be that long. The
        comet reaches its nearest point to
        the sun about the middle of April.
        Collision Impossible.
        While the orbits of the earth and
        the comet cross each other, they
        are not in the same plane. In oth?
        er words, it is no ''grade crossing."
        Thus, no collision of the earth and
        comet is possible.
        The Best Views.
        The best views of the comet for
        the general public will be from the
        middle of May, when it will be seen
        with the naked eye just before
        dawn a little south of where the
        sun rises and a little distance above
        the horizon; and again for a couple
        of weeks after May 18, when it will
        appear just after sunset, a little
        south of west and at a considerable
        height above the horizon.
        Finest Spectacle-The most in?
        teresting spectacle is expected to
        be afforded on May 1, when the
        comet nears Venus. The planet
        and the comet will be the same dis?
        tance from the earth and every one
        will be able to note their relative
        sizes. To see the comet then, one
        will have to be up before five
        o'clock in the morning. In fact,
        only the early risers will see the
        comet before it passes between the
        earth and the sun.
        Once Nearer.- In* 1835 Halley's
        comet came within 5,000,000 of the
        earth. As it did not then pass be?
        tween the earth and sun, the tail
        was pointed in another direction.
        The tail always paints away from
        the sun.
        No. Danger.? Eminent astrono?
        mers say there is no danger. It is
        not known for cerlain, when the
        comet passes between the earth and
        sun, whether or not the tail will be
        long enough to reach and envelop
        the earth. A California chemist
        claims to have discovered cyanogen
        gas (a deadly poison) in the tail.
        Prof. Fiost, of the Yerkes observa?
        tory, says: "The density of the
        comet is about the density of the
        vacuum in an electric bulb, and
        there cannot possibly be enough
        poisonous gas in it to hurt a fly."
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84037890/1910-05-18/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        On the evening of the 18th or morn
        ing of the 19th according to the ob
        servers longitude the comet passes
        between us and the sun and the earth
        Mill be enveloped In its tall If the
        latter Is long enough over 15000
        OOmUtsP H M
        If this evening is clear it will bo
        of great Interest and Iniiiortanoci to I
        look for illumination of the sky 1 In
        the early evening just after sunset
        the con ts tall will be in the east
        but a few hours later It will have pass
        ed over toward the West If as is
        sometimes supposed the tall Is a
        hollow cone of light there will be two
        times at which the sky In general is
        comparatively brightly illuminated
        separated by en Interval while wo
        are in the darker center of the tall
        Meanwhile observers on the opposite
        side of our planet will have tWe rait
        privilege of seeing the sun through thb
        comets head Only the extreme west
        ern portion of the United States
        is Included in Oils favored rtglon
        but as the comet enters upon the suiH
        dbk at 623 p m by Pacific stunt
        ard time null remains on it till 722
        tho transit will be visible all along
        the coast The comet passes almost
        squarely across the center of the nun
        from west to east
        Paradoxical as it may seem it I is
        probable that the ordinary observer
        tar with a small telescope and dark
        glasses will not be able to detect
        event the slightest trace of he com
        ets passage With powerful in
        struments the nucleus if solid might
        be seen as a dark speck against the
        sun If it is over 50 miles la diame
        ter but it is improbable that it is 1
        anything like so large for the whole
        amount of light reflected from tho
        comet when remote from the sun Is
        no more than a single mass 30 miles
        across would send us
        Transits of comets across the sun
        are very rare Tlo most remarkable
        previous Instance is that of the great
        comet of 1882 which though so bright
        that It could be seen close to thb sun
        In broad daylight with the naked eye
        vanished completely when In front of
        the HillS disk showing that It was
        practically transparent.
        </text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1910-05-21/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
        YERKES OBSBRVATORT, WIL
        LIAMS RAY. Wis., May 20.—Halley'a
        comet was under observation here
        from 7:40 to 8:35 tonight. Astronomers
        first observed it in the west through a
        four-inch telescope at 7:40. At 8:10
        the phenomenon *vas visible to tha
        naked eye and remained so until it
        became lost behind a. cloud bank at 8:35
        I>. m. It set at 9 o'clock.
        "The comet appeared as of tha
        brightness of a star of the second
        magnitude," said Prof. Edwin Frost.
        "No tail was observed. The exposures
        of the spectrum show principally a
        'continuous spectrum, which means it
        is chiefly due to reflected sunlight.
        The gaseous constituents were less
        conspicuous than when in the morning
        sky and appeared faint.
        "The comet will be visible to tha
        naked eye tomorrow night from S to 9
        p. m., in spite of a bright moon."
        </text>
      </result>

      <!-- Queries Used like "Comet Halley","Comet every 75 years", "Halley's comet tail"  -->
      <result>
        <id></id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id></id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id></id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id></id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

      <result>
        <id></id>
        <rel></rel>
        <text></text>
      </result>

    </results>
  </topic>

</topics>
